Ravi Shukla

Revenue & Operations





SKILLS

Excellent Communication

Advance Excel & MS Tools

Working Knowledge of SQL & Python

Relationship & Team Management

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth

06th Feb 1995

Nationality

Indian

VISA Status

Employment -Visit Visa

Marital status

Single

ABOUTME

A talented and well organized Operations professional with around 6 years of experience across F&B and Hotel Industry. I worked on high impact strategic projects and delivered positive outcomes. I always use MS Excel and G sheet for data management. I'm very good in Excel, Data Management, Operations, Team Management & Relationship Management. I also know Basics of SQL & Python. Working with OYO Rooms I scaled Food Business from 3 Cr to 10 Cr per month and also handled a team of supervisors and worked on multiple end to end projects and delivered high level of productivity.

WORK EXPERIENCE

F & B Executive | Revenue Operations

OYO Rooms / India / Nov 2018 - Oct 2021

- Worked with senior leaders and helped them to get insights from the revenue data
- Activating and Deactivating Food services at properties
- Leading online and offline sales promotional campaigns to increase the revenue
- Driven & Scaled Meal plan business across 3500 Smart & Self Operated hotels
- Solving process related issues in collaboration with internal and external stakeholders
- \bullet On-boarding and De-boarding of OYO kitchens at online platforms to get online Food orders
- \bullet Coordinating with ground staff and taking real time sales (F&B Sales) status and their feedback
- \bullet Helping my leaders to implement new revenue strategies and aligning the related teams for the same
- Worked on multiple end to end projects and delivered high level of productivity (IRD, PreBook Meals, Online Food Delivery, Cloud Kitchens)
- Personally worked on Low performing properties and aligned a team of F&B supervisors to push the daily business.

Credit Counselor

Creditas Solutions Pvt Ltd. / India / May 2017 - Oct 2018

- Assessed credit worthiness of applicants based on investigative findings
- Developed the financial and credit worthiness of commercial accounts
- Established and monitored new/existing credit lines for customers by performing financial statement analysis
- Developed efficient procedures in reviewing, analyzing, evaluating credit risks and providing solutions to complex problems encountered by customers
- Coordinating with analysts' team for simple and routine credit risk analysis and Negotiate credit disputes with high-level bank and loan office personnel.

Reservation | Sales Associate

OYO Rooms / India / June 2016 - May 2017

- Worked as a Reservation Executive.
- Worked on sales leads and ensured maximum booking conversion. (40% conversion rate)
- Single Handedly worked on App Booking Cancellation Project and retained maximum bookings
- I was the top performer in the team for many months

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree of Commerce -CSJM Kanpur University / India / 2018

Other Skills

Sales, Client Relationship Management, Credit Analyst, Food & Beverage, Customer Service, Teamwork, Hospitality

Microsoft Office & Google Tools, Data Management and Analysis